Guide to the Herman Axelbank Motion Picture Film Collection 1896-1977
Hoover Institution Archives
- Russian regiment on parade in honor of 300th anniversary of Romanov dynasty (28-37) anniversary celebration at Kremlin; crowds; priests (37-55) Duma in session; illus. of Grigorii Petrovskii, one of the Bolshevik deputies, being ejected from Duma (55-65) groups of Duma deputies, Senators; two men 
  Rodzianko, Mikhail Vladimirovich; Aleksei Nikolaevich, Tsarevich; Purishkevich, Vladimir Mitrofanovich; Nicholas II, Emperor; Miliukov, Pavel Nikolaevich; Alexandra, Empress Consort of Nicholas II, Emperor; Ol'ga Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Tat'iana Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Mariia Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Anastasiia Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Nikolai Nikolaevich, Grand Duke; Romanov, House of--Anniversaries
  Military ceremonies--Tsarist period; Processions--Tsarist period
  Duma
  Sound: 28-37; 50-89
- Kaiser Wilhelm II visits Krupp Works at Essen; Kaiser reviews hussar regiment; Kaiser at maneuvers on Tempelhof Grounds, Berlin; German soldiers drilling; pontoon bridge exercises; Kaiser and business leaders; Kaiser foxhunting; Kaiser and King Ludwig of Bavaria (173-246), 1913; Segment 3; 07:09:18 (Reel 8)
  173 (27/201)
  Wilhelm II, German Emperor; Ludwig III, King of Bavaria Krupp'sche Gusstahlfabrik, Essen; Military maneuvers--Germany; Military ceremonies--Germany
  Germany; Essen, Germany; Berlin
  Sound: 221-246
- Tsar, Empress, daughters, Tsarevich (carried) visit Sevastopol naval base (246-251) Tsar, daughters, Tsarevich return from motorboat trip; Tsar and daughters enter carriage (252-277) map of Russia in 1913; Tsar, Empress, and children participating in ceremony during celebration of 300th anniversary of Romanov dynasty (278-295) French soldiers digging trenches; rifle drill (295-298) Kaiser at parade in Berlin (298-309) Emperor Franz Joseph inspecting troops (299-313) ceremony with Nicholas II kissing Imperial Guards; daughters in the background (313-318) Tsar and his family visit the King and Queen of Romania, June 1914;receiving line; Tsarevich (walking); Tsar and King on horseback (318-372), 1913-1914; Segment 4; 07:14:53 (Reel 8)
  246 (27/228)
  Wilhelm II, German Emperor; Franz Joseph I, Emperor of Austria; Carol I, King of Romania; Elizabeth, Queen Consort of Carol I, King of Romania; Nicholas II, Emperor; Alexandra, Empress Consort of Nicholas II, Emperor; Ol'ga Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Tat'iana Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Mariia Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Anastasiia Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Aleksei Nikolaevich, Tsarevich; Romanov, House of--Anniversaries
  Visits of state; Military maneuvers--France; Military ceremonies--Tsarist period; Military ceremonies--Germany; Military ceremonies--Austria
  Sevastopol; Germany; Berlin; Romania; France; Austria A; D. Map
- State visit of Poincaire, July 1914;Poincaire met by ships from Baltic Fleet; Tsar on his yacht escorts Poincaire to St. Petersburg; military parade in Poincaire's honor; cavalry; Empress and entourage (0-50) after assassination of Franz Ferdinand at Sarajevo, assassin, Princip, captured; Kaiser with Hindenburg; Hindenburg and Ludendorff; German attack (50-91) Kaiser and General Staff (91-97) Tsar confers with ministers (97-102) St. Petersburg on the day war declared; patriotic demonstrations; Winter Palace Square; Tsar and Empress on balcony of Winter Palace; columns of soldiers on parade; off to war (102-130) Russian artillery; German-Russian trench battles (130-190) crowd scenes; common people; lines of men waiting to be inducted; tearful farewells; wounded; corpses; fleeing civilians; battle scenes (190-227), 1914; Segment 1; 2 30 + (Reel 9)
  0 (2/432)
  Poincaire, Raymond, Pres. France; Princip, Gavrilo; Nicholas II, Emperor; Alexandra, Empress Consort of Nicholas II, Emperor; Wilhelm II, German Emperor; Hindenburg, Paul von; Ludendorff, Erich
  Visits of state; Military ceremonies--Tsarist period; Wounded in battle; World War, 1914-1918--Patrotic response to; Soldiers' bodies, Disposition of; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--German front
  Leningrad; Sarajevo; Yugoslavia
  A; B. Battle scenes; capture of Princip?
  Sound: 0-19; 51-91 (79-82 refers to Civil War); 103-112; 191-227
- Photo of Lenin; reproduction of title page of Imperialism, Highest Stage of Capitalism; Albert Thomas, French Socialist Minister of Munitions (227-257) Russian cavalry (257-263) artillery (263-268) Grand Duke Nikolai Nikolaevich (269-274) Russian field telephone (274-277) Russian cannon firing (277-289) infantry charge (289-302) Russian dead; cudgel allegedly used to finish off Russian wounded by Germans (film shot by Ivan Dored, combat cameraman with Russian army); wounded at tent hospital (302-311) infantry attack through forest; Russian cannon (311-323) cavalry enters Austrian town; Austrian prisoners eating (323-332) cossack cavalry enters town of Pochæv; monastery at Pochæv; while Germans there they removed monks' skeletons from tombs; Russian soldiers shown putting skeletons back (332-367), 1914; Segment 2 (Reel 9)
  227 (2/489)
  Thomas, Albert; Dored, Ivan; Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich; Nikolai Nikolaevich, Grand Duke
  Monasteries; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--Galician front; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--German front; Wounded in battle; Prisoners of war--Austria; Pochævskaia Uspenskaia lavra; World War, 1914-1918--Atrocities; Telephone, Field; World War, 1914-1918--Wounded, hospitals, etc.; World War, 1914-1918--Prisons and prisoners Pochæv
  Sound: 227-257; 289-302
- Grave of Austrian officer, prisoner of war who died of his wounds (no. 362 on grave marker) (0-1) Metropolitan arrives to reconsecrate Pochæv Monastery; greets Russian soldiers; general decorates Russian soldiers; Metropolitan departs (1-30) Russian officer at Division Headquarters; general reviews Russian division on Galician Front; Imperial Russian battle flag; infantry; cavalry (30-62) priests bless troops before battle; Iliodor the "mad monk" blessing troops (62-124) Russian supply trucks, armored trucks; trench warfare in the snow (124-228) Austrian prisoners of war marching; prisoners being disarmed (228-268) graves (268-274) Petrograd; women in munitions plants (274-291) Russian soldiers marching to front (291-294) Armenian conscripts drilling before going to the front (294-299), 1914-1915; Segment 1 (Reel 10)
  0(2/524)
  Trufanov, Sergei Mikhailovich
  Orthodox Eastern Church, Russian; Pochævskaia Uspenskaia lavra; Monasteries; Soldiers' bodies, Disposition of; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--Galician front; Munition workers; Prisoners of war--Austria; World War, 1914-1918-Prisons and prisoners; Military ceremonies--Tsarist period; Women workers Pochæv; Leningrad
  Sound: 1-32; 41-62; 125-189; 275-299 (refers to 1917 and Civil War)
- Tsar at front with Grand Duke Nikolai Nikolaevich; Tsar at front reviewing troops (299-334), 1915; Segment 2; 2:51:20 (Reel 10)
  299 (2/590)
  Nicholas II, Emperor; Nikolai Nikolaevich, Grand Duke
  World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--German front; Military ceremonies--Tsarist period
  Sound: 309-313
- Baku oil fields (334-344) mine sweeper of Black Sea Fleet laying siege to Trebizond; Russian ship shelling causeway bridge to cut communications between Turkish Army and Trebizond (344-369), 1916; Segment 3 (Reel 10)
  334 (2/598)
  World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--Turkish front; World War, 1914-1918--Naval operations
  Trebizond, Turkey; Turkey; Baku; Black Sea Region
- Capture of Trebizond, April 17, 1916--Russian reinforcements land on coast (0-31) Turks surrender (31-48) view of Trebizond port, city, bay (48-80) Turkish shells; heavy garrison guns captured by Russians (80-100) delegation of Trebizond residents, carrying white flag, headed by U.S. Consul, Keyser, marching to meet Russian commander; Trebizond residents meet Russians at U.S. Consulate with bread, salt, flowers (100-119) Russian cavalry patrol destroys Turkish communications (119-135), 1916; Segment 1 (Reel 11)
  0 (3/006)
  Keyser, U.S. Consul in Trebizond
  World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--Turkish front
  Trebizond, Turkey; Turkey
- Russian Air Force on Turkish Front--Voisin fighter plane, pusher-type, propeller in rear; pilot suits up, gets into plane for bombing raid over Turkish lines (135-168) on the way to Erzerum (Erzerum captured Feb. 16, 1916)--infantry patrol crossing plank bridge over stream (168-185) cavalry patrol; cavalry patrol crossing stream (185-188) fighter plane in the air; on the ground; pilot examines stack of bombs he will drop by hand from open cockpit; shells exploding in the distance; puffs of smoke (188-227) Russian landing parties in boats next to Black Sea Fleet ships; wounded being loaded on battleship to be taken to Sevastopol; unloading horses from transport ship; landing parties in boats next to ships; ruins on the road to Erzerum (227-250), 1916; Segment 2 (Reel 11)
  135 (3/079)
  World War, 1914-1918--Aerial operations; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--Turkish front; Wounded in battle; Horses, Transport of; World War, 1914-1918--Naval operations; World War, 1914-1918--Wounded, hospitals, etc.
  Erzerum, Turkey; Turkey
  Sound: 185 (refers to Civil War)
- Russian Air Force Lieutenant Mertesalov takes plane up for bombing raid; over Turkish lines; forced down by enemy fire, Mertesalov makes emergency landing in a cornfield; Mertesalov back on the ground, with pipe, plane, and ground crew (250-307) staff headquarters in a Turkish villa; General Wrangel (307-311) Russians advancing in the mountains through a narrow pass; infantry; cavalry; artillery on carts pulled by horses (311-339), 1916; Segment 3 (Reel 11)
  250 (3/132)
  Mertesalov, Lieutentant, Imperial Russian Air Force; Vrangel', Petr Nikolaevich, Baron
  World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--Turkish front; World War, 1914-1918--Aerial operations
  Turkey
- Advance post on mountain; Russian trenches; soldier pours himself a cup of tea; soldiers digging trenches; Turkish officers; Russian guns firing (0-82) field hospital; wounded on stretchers; nurse in tent innoculates soldiers (82-109) cavalry patrol mining bridge; mountain battery shelling Turkish lines; shells exploding (109-159) cossack cavalry charge (159-181) view from trench during battle (181-183), 1916; Segment 1 (Reel 12)
  0 (3/171)
  Wounded in battle; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--Turkish front; World War, 1914-1918--Wounded, Hospitals, etc.; Soldiers Turkey
  Sound: 160-166 (Refers to Civil War)
- Exchange of Russian and German wounded prisoners; Red Cross representative; shell shocked German; group shot of wounded Russian and German prisoners (on crutches, amputees); young Russian soldiers around a table drinking (183-278), May 21, 1916; Segment 2 (Reel 12)
  183 (3/239)
  Soldiers; Wounded in battle; World War, 1914-1918--Wounded, hospitals, etc.; World War, 1914-1918--Prisons and prisoners; Prisoners of war--Germany; Prisoners of war--Finland--Tornio Tornio, Finland; Finland
- Tsar at the front; group shot surrounded by generals and high ranking officers; Tsar at Red Cross hospital (278-291) war relief bazaar in Petrograd; Tsar on white horse; Empress, Anastasiia, Ol'ga, Tat'iana in bazaar booth; Tsar, on foot, appears to be trying to keep automobile between himself and the camera (291-338) Russian Army retreats; equipment and cavalry cross river; corpses (338-353) Tsar and Grand Duke Nikolai Nikolaevich at the front; Tsar arrives in Mogilev, accompanied by Chief of Staff IAnushkevich and the Grand Duke; General Alekseev delivers a report (353-376), 1916; Segment 3 (Reel 12)
  278 (3/271)
  Nicholas II, Emperor; Alexandra, Empress Consort of Nicholas II, Emperor; Ol'ga Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Tat'iana Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Anastasiia Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Nikolai Nikolaevich, Grand Duke; IAnushkevich, Nikolai Nikolaevich; Alekseev, Mikhail Vasil'evich
  Wounded in battle; World War, 1914-1918--Wounded, hospitals, etc.; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--German front; Bazaars, Charitable; World War, 1914-1918--Charities Leningrad; Mogilev
  Sound: 353-376
- General Brusilov, sitting at a table, smiling and talking (0-8) Tsar's emissary, General IAnushkevich, attends ceremonies at the opening of a railroad built by Russian engineers between Julfa an the Persian border and Tabriz (project was begun in 1907); Persian Crown Prince Mohammed Hassan Mirza cuts ribbon; Russian and Persian dignitaries get into cars; train surrounded by crowds of people; cavalry honor guards line tracks; dignitaries review Persian troops; dignitaries pose for camera; ribbon cutting; Russian dignitary makes speech; Crown Prince, IAnushkevich, and others watch Persian cavalry jumping exhibition; soldiers in calisthenics demonstration; acrobats; trick riding exhibition (8-332) French reception of Russian brigade as it disembarks from ship in France (332-353), 1916 (railroad ceremony, June, 1916); Segment 1; 3:27:20 (Reel 13)
  0 (3/305)
  IAnushkevich, Nikolai Nikolaevich; Mohammed Hassan Mirza, Crown Prince of Persia; Brusilov, Aleksei Alekseevich
  Railroads--Iran; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--France Iran; Tabriz, Iran; Julfa, Iran; France
  Captions in English
- Priests bless troops; Tsar and Tsarevich review troops (0-106) Tsar, Empress, and daughters at same military review; soundtrack says this is the last moving picture film taken of the imperial family (106-118) Russian soldiers, eating, during a snowstorm (118-138), late autumn-winter 1916; Segment 1 (Reel 14)
  0 (3/408)
  Nicholas II, Emperor; Alexandra, Empress Consort of Nicholas II, Emperor; Ol'ga Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Tat'iana Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Mariia Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Anastasiia Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Aleksei Nikolaevich, Tsarevich Orthodox Eastern Church, Russian; Military ceremonies--Tsarist period; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--German front; Soldiers
  Sound: 107-118
- Lieutenant Colonel Gruzinov, Commander of the Troops of the Moscow Military District, reviews troops on Red Square (138-157) poorer residents of Petrograd; women and children; market with almost nothing available for sale (157-167) photos of Rasputin; poster of Rasputin; photo of IUsupov (167-199) wounded being unloaded, carried on stretchers to hospital; wounded lying outside full hospitals; soldiers' corpses lying in snowy field; soldiers' corpses being dumped from cart onto field (199-228) street scene near Alexander III statue in Petrograd (228-237) view of Putilov Factory; factory whistle; leaflets being handed out; workers leaving Putilov Factory; strike at Putilov Factory; strike leaders addressing crowd of workers (237-254) street demonstrations in Petrograd, including one on Znamenskaia Square (254-293) garrison troops, called out to surpress demonstrations, go over to the revolution-Keksholm Regiment, Pavlovskii Regiment (293-356) soldiers marching; in cars; with armored car; Tauride Palace, exterior; interior; Duma in session; exterior; crowds with banners (356-371), Dec. 1916-March 1917 (N.S.); Segment 2; 03:55 03:40 (Reel 14)
  138 (3/444)
  Gruzinov, Lieutenant Colonel, Commander of the Troops of the Moscow Military District; Rasputin, Grigorii Efimovich; IUsupov, Feliks Feliksovich, kniaz'
  World War, 1914-1918--Wounded, hospitals, etc.; Wounded in battle; Military ceremonies--Tsarist period; Demonstrations--February Revolution; Pavlovskii Regiment; Keksholm Regiment; Strikes; Soldiers' bodies, Disposition of; Soldiers, Revolutionary; February Revolution (March 1917 N.S.); Putilov Factory; Duma Moscow; Leningrad
  A; B. Putilov Factory scenes. D. Photos of Rasputin, Iusupov
  Sound: 138-371 (with gaps)
- Soviet of Workers' and Soldiers' Deputies; crowds in front of Tauride Palace; Volynskii and Keksholm Regiments march to Duma to pledge loyalty to new government (0-31) Rodzianko; Provisional Government leader addresses crowd from steps of Tauride Palace; revolutionary soldiers in trucks; soldiers drinking tea in Tauride Palace (31-64) destruction of Schlüsselburg Prison, civil records and deeds, tsarist emblems; gutted buildings on Znamenskaia Square (64-117) troops of the Moscow Military District (on horseback); crowds; police agents apprehended; soldiers with sacks of grain; peoples's militia; captured gendarmes in prison; crowds; demonstrations in Moscow; soldiers cheering; poster with "war to victory" slogan; demonstration in Moscow; Gruzinov and others of Moscow Military District; demonstrations; banners; crippled war veterans; demonstrations in Moscow; Petrograd--crowds, red flag; sacked police station (117-324), March 1917; Segment 1; 04:00 04:09 (Reel 15)
  0 (4/011)
  Rodzianko, Mikhail Vladimirovich; Gruzinov, Lieutenant Colonel, Commander of the Troops of the Moscow Military District
  Duma; Provisional Government; Police; Demonstrations--February Revolution; Soldiers, Revolutionary; Soviet of Workers' and Soldiers' Deputies; February Revolution (March 1917 N.S.); Volynskii Regiment; Keksholm Regiment; Militia; Okhrana Leningrad; Moscow
  Sound: 0-324 (with gaps)
- Prisoners being released; filing out of prison door; official reads a proclamation to them; they line up with a banner facing camera for a group picture; official delivers speech to them; they toss him in the air (0-50) crowds, smiling, waving (aware of camera) on Nevskii Prospekt (50-71) Purishkevich giving a speech to crowd in front of Tauride Palace (71-91) Kerensky in civilian clothes coming out a door (91-98) political prisoner released after 25 years in solitary confinment (98-101) revolutionary soldiers parading in the streets of Petrograd (101-131) Sir Alfred Knox, British military attache (131-159) militia on guard in Petrograd (159-161) Guchkov (161-163), March 1917; Segment 1; 04:09:10 (Reel 16)
  0 (4/167)
  Knox, Alfred William Fortescu, Sir; Purishkevich, Vladimir Mitrofanovich; Kerenskii, Aleksandr Fedorovich; Guchkov, Aleksandr Ivanovich
  Military attaches, British; Prisoners, Political; Soldiers, Revolutionary; Militia; February Revolution (March 1917 N.S.); Prisoners
  Sound: 101-131
- Funeral of the martyrs of the February Revolution on Mars Field, Petrograd; crowds (over a million people attended); armored vehicles; people carrying the coffins; procession; banners (including banner of the Russian League of Working Women); bands (163-361), April 1917; Segment 2; 04: 18 (Reel 16)
  163 (4/229)
  Funeral service--Martyrs of February Revolution
  Sound: 340-361
- Funeral of the martyrs of the February Revolution (cont.)--funeral procession; banners; cannon salute; coffins in open grave; paper tag on each giving name of martyr (0-26) Duma, Provisional Government, and Petrograd Soviet figures--Guchkov; Rodzianko; widows of martyrs; Petrograd Garrison troops; Shul'gin; Guchkov; Vera Zasulich; Vera Figner; Gruzenberg, attorney, on Figner's right; Burtsev; Rodzianko; Guchkov; Miliukov; Steklov; Skobelev; Tsereteli; workers' militia; military band; crowds (26-127), April 1917; Segment 1; 04:19 (Reel 17)
  0 (4/296)
  Figner, Vera Nikolaevna; Shul'gin, Vasilii Vital'evich; Guchkov, Aleksandr Ivanovich; Rodzianko, Mikhail Vladimirovich; Zasulich, Vera Ivanovna; Burtsev, Vladimir L'vovich; Miliukov, Pavel Nikolaevich; Steklov, IUrii Mikhailovich; Skobelev, Matvei Ivanovich; Tsereteli, Iraklii Georgievich; Gruzenberg, Oskar Osipovich
  Soviet of Workers' and Soldiers' Deputies; Provisional Government; Funeral service--Martyrs of February Revolution; Duma
  Sound: 0-26; 57-127
- Duma leaders, in a group, including Miliukov, Konovalov (behind Miliukov), Shul'gin, Rodzianko; Executive Committee of the Petrograd Soviet, including Chkheidze, Skobelev; Provisional Government members Prince L'vov, Prime Minister; Miliukov, Foreign Minister; Executive Committee of the Petrograd Soviet, shown singly--Chkheidze, Chairman; Tsereteli; Avksent'ev; Kamenev; Shreider, first elected mayor of Petrograd; group shot of the Executive Committee; group of Duma leaders including Miliukov, Guchkov, Rodzianko (center); Guchkov removes hat (127-183), April 1917; Segment 2 (Reel 17)
  127 (4/335)
  Guchkov, Aleksandr Ivanovich; Konovalov, Aleksandr Ivanovich; Shul'gin, Vasilii Vital'evich; Miliukov, Pavel Nikolaevich; Chkheidze, Nikolai Semenovich; Skobelev, Matvei Ivanovich; L'vov, Georgii Evgen'evich, kniaz'; Tsereteli, Iraklii Georgievich; Avksent'ev, Nikolai Dmitrievich; Kamenev, Lev Borisovich; Shreider, Grigorii Il'ich; Rodzianko, Mikhail Vladimirovich Provisional Government; Duma; Soviet of Workers' and Soldiers' Deputies
  Sound: 127-183
- Photo of Lenin walking down a street with a group of associates (during his return to Russia); David R. Francis, American Ambassador; Francis Riggs, American military attache, with Norman Armour, First Secretary of the American Embassy; Chkheidze; Skobelev greets a member of the Petrograd Soviet (?); illus. from a book of Lenin on arrival in Petrograd, April 16, 1917;Ksheshinskaia Palace, Bolshevik headquarters; illus. from a book of Lenin speaking from balcony of Ksheshinskaia Palace; illus. from book of Lenin addressing Executive Committee of the Petrograd Soviet; front page of Lenin's April Theses (183-234), April 1917; Segment 3 (Reel 17)
  183 (4/352)
  Armour, Norman; Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich; Francis, David Rowland; Chkheidze, Nikolai Semenovich; Riggs, Francis; Skobelev, Matvei Ivanovich
  Military attaches, American; Diplomats, American
  Sound: 183-202
- Peter and Paul Fortress Commander; street scene, Petrograd, April 1917--streetcars, cars, horse-drawn vehicles (234-249) Peter Kropotkin and his wife (249-255) Provisional Government session (255-273) two Provisional Government(?) figures; Avksent'ev and others arriving in a car; Ekaterina Breshko-Breshkovskaia (273-289) soldiers dancing (289-308), April 1917; Segment 4; 04:26: (Reel 17)
  234 (4/366)
  Breshko-Breshkovskaia, Ekaterina Konstantinovna (Verigo); Kropotkin, Petr Alekseevich, kniaz'; Kropotkina, Sofiia Grigor'evna (Anan'eva); Avksent'ev, Nikolai Dmitrievich Soldiers; Provisional Government
  Sound: 249-255; 268-290 (with gaps)
- May Day celebration, 1917--parades; Skobelev is cheered and thrown in the air; Winter Palace Square; Kamenev addressing the crowd; Molotov (lower left); illus. from book of Lenin speaking from a truck; parades, banners (308-389), May 1, 1917; Segment 5 (Reel 17)
  308 (4/387)
  Skobelev, Matvei Ivanovich; Kamenev, Lev Borisovich; Molotov, Viacheslav Mikhailovich
  May Day (Labor holiday), 1917; Processions--Provisional Government period
  Sound: 308-389 (with gaps)
- May Day, 1917--parades, banners in Petrograd; May Day parade at Kronstadt; Dybenko, leader of Kronstadt sailors (0-69) General Radko Dimitriev, Bulgarian in Russian service, reviews troops of the Provisional Government (69-116) Florence Harper, correspondent for Leslie's Weekly, getting into a carriage in Petrograd; Emmeline Pankhurst reading and discussing a newspaper article with a companion at a cafe table in Petrograd (116-147), May 1917; Segment 1 (Reel 18)
  0 (4/411)
  Dybenko, Pavel Efimovich; Dimitriev, Radko; Harper, Florence MacLeod; Pankhurst, Emmeline (Goulden) May Day (Labor holiday), 1917; Military ceremonies--Provisional Government period
  Leningrad; Kronstadt
  Sound: 0-69